# **Adam Hutson**

4936 S. Butterfield Pl. Battlefield, MO 65619

Phone: (417) 224-5212 E-Mail: adam.hutson@yahoo.com

## Summary

DataStax MVP for Apache Cassandra

Certified, Experienced & Passionate about all things data.

Seasoned data professional with experience designing & developing large-scale, high transaction database systems. Expert in NoSQL technologies with production experience in both building NoSQL solutions and migrating existing relational data to them. Diversified skill sets covering Microsoft, Sun, Unix and Open Source software. Offer a unique background of software development, database administration and reliability operations.

## Experience

## FireEye

January 2019 - Present Milpitas, CA

## Senior Staff Data Engineer, Helix Security Platform

April 2020 - Present

- Manage data architecture for Helix Security Platform
- Create working POCs of architecture designs in distributed, relational, key-value, & document data stores
- Use Go, Java, Python, ElasticSearch, Kafka, Redis, MySQL, Postgres, DynamoDB, Kinesis

## Staff Data Engineer, CloudPIE - Data Engineering

January 2019 - April 2020 (1 year 4 months)

- Provide Elasticsearch, Redis, Cassandra, Kafka, & Zookeeper as managed services for FireEye applications
- Provide expertise in data modeling for supported data stores.
- Build automation tooling to deploy/configure data stores.
- Build automation for operations, maintenance, patching, backups, & restores of data stores.
- Build dashboards and alerting for data store performance visibility.
- Ensure automation tooling & data store configuration meets FedRAMP compliance on AWS GovCloud.
- Use Terraform, Packer, Consul, Vault, Ansible, Jenkins on AWS Cloud & GovCloud

#### Confluent

February 2018 - January 2019 (11 months) Palo Alto, CA

#### **Solutions Architect**

- Provide expertise on Apache Kafka & Zookeeper, Kafka Streams, KSQL, & Kafka sink/source connectors.
- Develop/advocate best practices, gather/validate critical product feedback for Confluent Platform.
- Help customers overcome their operational challenges.
- Weekly travel to customers location, in post-sales, professional services scenario.
- Write documentation, knowledge base articles, reference architecture material, & design patterns.

#### **DataStax**

November 2016 - February 2018 (1 year 4 months) San Francisco Bay Area

## Senior Site Reliability Engineer, DataStax Managed Cloud

July 2017 - February 2018 (8 months)

- Designing/Building out Site Reliability tools to ensure MTTR/MTTD/MTTF metrics & SLA for customers infra.
- Providing in-person, white glove service to onboard customers' data/services into the DMC platform.
- Mentoring new SRE hires on DevOps team.

## Senior Software Engineer, DataStax Managed Cloud

November 2016 - July 2017 (9 months)

- Founding member of DataStax Managed Cloud
- Designing/Building platform automation for the DataStax Managed Cloud (DMC) hosted DSE solution.
- Recipient of Engineering Excellence Award

## DataScale (Acquired by DataStax)

July 2015 - November 2016 (1 year 5 months) San Francisco Bay Area

#### **Data Architect**

DataScale is an early stage, stealth startup building products & services with Spark, Cassandra & Kafka.

- Design/Build automated platform to managed hosted Apache Cassandra as a service.
- Onboard new customers' data/services into DataScale platform
- Maintain constant touch points with all customers to stay abreast of data/service changes
- Evaluate all customer application code bases before onboard into DataScale platform
- Provide all Technical Support for customers
- Write weekly blogs on Cassandra at http://datascale.io/category/data/
- Maintain all content/engagement for @DataScaleInc Twitter handle
- Presented two talks at DataStax's Cassandra Summit 2016
- Presented at numerous Cassandra Meet-ups around the US & Canada
- Recipient of DataStax MVP Award for Apache Cassandra https://academy.datastax.com/planet-cassandra/mvps
- DataScale was successfully acquired by DataStax to be renamed DataStax Managed Cloud

#### CloudPassage

November 2014 - July 2015 (9 months) San Francisco Bay Area

### **Data Architect**

Responsible for defining and developing the CloudPassage Halo data model, ensuring that the entire data stack, including Cassandra and PostgreSQL are optimized for high-performance and high-availability in a highly dynamic and hyper growth environment.

- Thorough review of current data model and schema
- Strategy for enabling hyper-growth and optimization of data model
- Moving away from licensed DataStax products and support and using open source tools
- Implementing a plan for driving advanced and predictive analytics from the data model
- Providing information on tools for data model optimization

• Working closely with development and devops to ensure we have the right infrastructure stack and it is configured correctly

#### **American National**

August 2014 - November 2014 (4 months) Springfield, Missouri

## **Staff Database Architect**

- Design/implement snowflake Data Warehouse for Insurance Claims data using SQL Server
- Design/implement multiple Analysis Services Cubes for business analysts
- Design/implement de-normalized relational database for reporting users
- Design metrics dashboard for C-level executive users
- Implement Scrum development practices
- Languages: TSQL
- Databases: SQL Server
- Operating Systems: Windows

## Expedia

July 2010 - August 2014 (4 years 2 months) Springfield, Missouri

## Senior Data Engineer

- Creation of multi-terabyte Cassandra NoSQL data stores
- Migration of existing relational SQL Server data to new NoSQL design
- Development of Java backend code to interface with both SQL & NoSQL engines
- Development of Python & Bash scripting for managing data movement in Amazon's S3 buckets
- Development of OpsCode Chef recipes for automated creation of Linux VMs in Amazon's EC2 environment
- Design data structures for both relational and NoSQL data needs
- Design & maintain SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) packages
- Conversion of Data Transformation Services (DTS) to SQL Server Integration Services (SSIS) packages
- Optimize, tune, & test SQL queries for peak performance and to alleviate concurrency & deadlock pressure
- Languages: TSQL, C#, Java, Python, Bash & DOS scripting
- Databases: SQL Server, Cassandra, MySQL, Oracle
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux CentOS, Mac OS X

#### Hutson Software, LLC

May 2007 - Present Springfield, Missouri

## Owner

- Creation of Commission Calculation application for AutoCAD sales/software company. Written in C# against MS Dynamics CRM in SQL Server.
- Creation of stand alone Crystal Report 2011 application & assembly in C# against MySQL. Features include: Savable parameters, central report management, ability to clone reports, and a report creation wizard.
- Creation of Home Healthcare Dashboard application in WPF & C# for viewing customized aggregations of healthcare metrics.
- Creation of Beauty Salon CMS application in C# & SQL CE for maintaining client information, purchases, & schedules.
- Creation and maintenance of Crystal Reports XIr2 for clients

#### Karmak

December 2007 - July 2010 (2 years 8 months) Springfield, Missouri

#### DBA/Software Developer

- SQL Server database design & performance tuning.
- Create SQL Server database sync scripts for every product release and service pack.

- Assist Installations team on SQL Server & product installation/upgrades.
- Implement database version control through Visual Studio 2008 Database Edition and Team Foundation Server.
- Provide support in data conversions from legacy mainframe databases.
- C# & VB.NET Client/Server WinForm development of main product.
- Lead developer for integration of Reporting Services & Crystal Reports viewers in .NET reporting solution to display system reports.
- Lead developer for creation of ad-hoc Reporting Services application.

### **Accenture Duck Creek**

April 2007 - December 2007 (9 months) Bolivar, Missouri

## **Senior Programmer**

- C#, ASP.NET, XML, XSLT, & JavaScript development/maintenance of main product.
- Improve overall database performance through analysis of bottlenecks, deadlocks, I/O utilization, and connection pooling.
- Develop C# database migration application to manage database sync scripts between product releases.
- Mentor other developers in SQL Server database development and performance.
- Agile development methodology.

#### McKesson

January 2004 - April 2007 (3 years 4 months) Springfield, Missouri

## **Software Engineer II**

- C#, VB.NET, & VB6 WinForm development for main product, ancillary products, and custom solutions.
- Technical Lead for Offshore development project; manage 5 developers in India for completion of code conversion of 93 apps and 212 reports.
- Develop & Implement Business Intelligence application using Analysis Services Data Mart / Data Warehouse with Visual Basic 6 user interface that utilize Pivot Tables and Crystal Reports.
- Maintain mobile product for PDAs using C#, Windows Mobile 5.0 and SQL Server Mobile.
- Refactor code and database objects for government mandate Patient Safety standards of medication frequency.
- Develop VB.NET application to interact with MapQuest web services to automate driving directions.
- Develop SOAP web services to exchange data with third-party vendors.
- Maintain all Crystal Report applications in product.
- Mentor junior engineers in code development.

#### **Cox Health Systems**

August 2002 - January 2004 (1 year 6 months) Springfield, Missouri

#### **Data Analyst**

- Data analysis of hospital data for departmental requests off of Cerner Decision Support System and hospital mainframe databases.
- Develop Visual Basic 6 applications to streamline analysis timelines and provide repeatable consistency.
- Develop mining tool to screen scrape info from PDF documents of Press Ganey patient satisfaction surveys.
- Introduced Crystal Reports 7 as primary analysis delivery tool.

#### D3 Technologies

June 2001 - October 2001 (5 months) Springfield, Missouri

## Hardware/Software Specialist

Visual Basic 6 & AutoLISP automation for Computer Automated Drafting (CAD) software

• Diagnose and upgrade hardware on client machines.

## **Education**

Missouri State University BS, Computer Information Systems - (1997-2002)

# Certifications

MCTS, SQL Server 2008, Database Development - Microsoft, License 7582520

Certified Cassandra 1.1 Developer - Datastax